[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you and good morning.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢大家 早上好
This is Session 712, What's New
现在是会议 712
In Core Bluetooth.
核心蓝牙的新功能介绍
My name is Craig Dooley.
我是 Craig Dooley
I'm a Bluetooth Engineer here at
我是 Apple 的一名
Apple.
蓝牙工程师
I think we have some really good
今天
stuff to talk to you about
我有很多非常好的内容
today, so we'll start with a
想要与大家分享
brief introduction of where Core
我们今天的会议
Bluetooth is right now.
将会先对核心蓝牙做一些简短的介绍
We'll talk about some of the
我还会谈到一些
enhanced reliability features
我们今年所实现的
that we built for this year.
一些增强的可靠性特性
Talk about platform support.
提到支持的平台
We announced watchOS support
在我们的努力下
this year and we're really
wantchOS 已经在今年全面支持了
excited about that.
我们对此感到非常激动
A new feature for this year is
今年还有的一大新特性是
L2CAP channels.
L2CAP 通道
Then we'll go over some of the
我将首先带领大家回忆一下
best practices we've learned
我们近年来所做的测试工作
over the years, and finally
然后
we'll do a real world example of
我们将做一个
how to get the most out of Core
真实世界的例子
Bluetooth.
来充分展示核心蓝牙
So I'd like to start with a
所以
brief introduction.
我想以一个简短的介绍来开启我们今天的会议
Hopefully everybody knows but,
核心蓝牙
if you don't, Core Bluetooth is
是我们在 2011 年发布的
our framework that we released
与低功耗蓝牙外设
in 2011 to interact with
和配件
Bluetooth low energy peripherals
交互的
and accessories.
框架
And since we initially shipped
自从我们发布了这个框架以来
the framework, we've just seen
我们看到了
amazing creativity come out of
来自配件生产商
accessory manufacturers and app
和 App 开发人员的
developers.
惊人创意
We're so pleased to see what
我们很高兴的看到你们的
you've done with it.
骄人成果
So when we started off, we knew
所以当我们开始这个项目以后
that health and fitness and were
我们就知道健康与健身
going to be big areas.
将成为着重发展的领域
We've seen lots of things like
我们看到了很多创意
smart scales, running sensors,
如智能体重秤
fitness devices that you can
运动传感器
wear all day.
以及可以全天穿着的健身设备
But the creativity has been
但是
awesome to watch.
很多创意光听起来就觉得很棒
So things like toys and
就像那种看起来像玩具的产品
connected accessories for kids.
或者是为了小朋友们所做的外设
We were really excited to see
所以
the Swift Playground's
我们非常期待 Swift Playground 今年的
announcements this year, and
更新
really making things more
这让小朋友们
interactive for children and
或者
people who are first learning to
刚刚接触编程的人
code.
也能更多地参加进来
And we love seeing how easy it
我们喜欢看到人们
is for people to take things
容易地通过 App 来控制传感器
like sensors or buttons or
按钮
switches and enable those
或者开关
through their apps and enable
甚至
them wirelessly.
进行无线控制
And then things have gone in
之后的事情
directions that we couldn't have
甚至向着我们没有想象到的方向
even imagined.
发展了起来
Things like connected goggles
比如
with head-mounted displays, just
将护目镜
awesome creativity that's come
与头戴式显示器相连接
out of this community.
这是一个非常棒的创意
So I want to start this talk
所以我想说一句
just by saying thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
It's awesome for us to see what
我们很高兴的看到
you've been able to build with
大家可以通过这一技术
this technology, and we can't
做出这么多的成果
wait to see how you build even
我们更加迫不及待的看到
better accessories going forward
大家用我之后要谈论到的
with these enhancements we want
升级后的技术
to talk to you about today.
又将做出什么更加好的配件
And before we start, I just want
在我开始讲解之前
to mention there's a lot of
我想说一点
types of accessories that you
就是很多类型的配件
don't have to write any software
你都是不需要
for.
为它们编写任何软件的
So if you want to see things
所以
like what the currently playing
比如你想查看一下
music is on your device, you can
当前在你的设备上
implement the Apple Media
播放的是哪个音乐
Service and the device will take
你可以使用 Apple Media 服务
care of all of that for you.
然后你的设备就可以帮你做这一切
Things like iBeacon or HID
像 iBeacon
devices, you don't have to write
或者 HID 这种设备
any software for those.
你不需要为它们编写任何软件
And we've seen really good
我们也已经看到了
adoption for those as well.
有关它们的很好的使用
But today is going to be about
但是
Core Bluetooth and how your
今天我们是讲解核心蓝牙
device can talk to your
以及你的设备是
accessory.
如何与配件交互的
So stepping back to stage 1,
所以
Bluetooth Low Energy has two
让我们退回到第一步
roles.
低功耗蓝牙主要有两个功能
There's a central that can look
首先是
for devices that are around your
作为一个中心
environment, and there are
可以搜寻你周围环境中的设备
peripherals that can beacon to
再者是作为外设
the world that they're there.
可以向外部环境表明它们的位置
They can either send out data or
它们可以发送数据
just let their presence be
或者
known.
仅仅是表明它们的存在
So if you have simple things
所以
that you want to send out like
如果你想发送一些简单的数据
the current temperature or the
如当前温度
time, you can do that and you
或者时间
can actually connect device to
你可以轻易地实现
device as well.
甚至你也可以将设备与设备相连接
iOS and Mac devices are allowed
iOS 和 Mac 设备
to be both the central and the
在连接中
peripheral side of the
都是既可以作为中心
connection.
也可以作为外围
After you find this device
当你查找到
that's around you, you can
一个你周围的设备之后
connect to your device and then
你可以
you have bidirectional
将它连接到你的设备
communication through what's
然后
called the GATT Protocol.
你可以通过 GATT 协议来进行双向通信
The GATT Protocol takes all of
GATT 协议
your data and it exposes them in
传输所有数据
a hierarchy called services and
并将其公开在
characteristics.
称为服务和特征的层次结构中
We represent these in Core
在核心蓝牙中
Bluetooth as a CB service.
我们将这些称为 CB 服务
And a CB service can contain
并且
characteristics inside of it.
CB 服务可以有一些内部特征
Most of the time, your Apple
大多数情况下
device is going to be the
你的苹果设备
central side of this connection
在一个连接中是作为中心的
and you connect to your
然后
peripheral.
你由此连接到外围设备
But you can also do this in
但是
reverse.
你也可以将这个情况反过来
So one example of this is your
所以
phone has its own GATT database
让我们举个例子
that exposes something like the
比如你的手机有自己的 GATT 数据库
current time service.
并且显示一些诸如时间服务的东西
So if it's useful for your
所以
accessory to get the current
如果对于你的配件来说
time, you can actually read that
获取当前时间是有用的
off of your phone.
它们就可以从你的手机读取当前时间
If you're looking to build these
如果
type of iDirectional
你想在 CB Central Manager 上
communications on CB Central
构建这些类型的 iDirectional 通信
manager, you can either retrieve
你可以通过
the connected peripherals if you
调用 retrieveConnectedPeripherals
know that your device is already
来看你的设备是否已经被连接
connected by calling
如果
retrieveConnectedPeripherals or
已被连接
if you have an identifier for an
你可以回复这些连接的外部设备
accessory you can call
或者
retrievePeripherals
如果你的配件有一个独特的标识符
(withidentifiers) and get
你可以通过调用 retrievePeripherals(withidentifiers)
handled back to your accessory.
来获得对于你配件的控制权
So let's move onto something new
接下来
for this year.
让我们谈论一些今年的新发展
As I mentioned, the health and
正如我之前提到的
fitness space has really popped
在核心蓝牙被研发出以后
up since Core Bluetooth was
健康和健身领域的发展
first announced.
迎来了蓬勃生机
And we find there's a whole
我们发现
class of devices that want to be
整天都有一大堆
connected all day.
想要连接的设备
Users want access to their data
用户不管在他们穿着这些设备的时候
as they're wearing it or
或者
throughout the night, and you
夜里的任何时候
want to make sure that your
都希望
connection to your Accessories
可以查看他们的数据
is reliable.
所以你必须保证你配件中的连接是可靠稳定的
So on iOS we allow you to be a
所以
background application.
在 iOS 上我们允许你做一个后台运行的 App
You can continue connecting out
你可以与你的配件保持连接
to your accessory or you can
或者
continue beaconing to the world
你可以通过 Xcode 中的
that you have data that's
这两个选项
available by using these two
来继续向外界
options in Xcode.
发送可用的数据
In you can either choose to use
你可以选择
your Bluetooth LE accessories or
使用你的蓝牙 LE 配件
act as a Bluetooth LE accessory
或者
if a peripheral is the role that
直接将自身作为一个蓝牙 LE 配件
you want to implement.
如果说你想要实现的是一个外部设备的功能
But we allow you to go even
但是
further than that, so if you're
我们允许你的功能更进一步
acting as a central, you can do
如果你是作为一个中心
things like Scan for new devices
你可以通过具体化
by specifying a service or
一项服务
Connect to an accessory you
来完成搜索新设备
already known about and even if
你也可以
your application is Jetson from
连接到一个已知设备
the system from memory reasons,
即使你的应用是来自存储系统的 Jetson
Core Bluetooth will continue to
核心蓝牙也会持续的
look for those devices for you.
帮你搜索这些设备
If we were to do this in code,
如果
at the time that you initialize
我们要用代码实现这个功能
a CBCentralManager, you pass
在你初始化 CBCentralManager 时
this RestoreIdentifier.
你要传递 RestoreIdentifier
This is just a string that
这只是一个
identifies your session that you
用于标识
want to continue going.
你要继续进行的会话的字符串
And if we can complete those
如果
actions on your behalf, like
我们可以代替你
connecting to your accessory,
完成这些操作
even if it's a week after your
例如
application was launched, we'll
连接到你的配件
relaunch your application and
即使这将会在你的 App 启用后再花费一周的时间
give you this callback.
我们也将重新启动你的 App 并为你提供此回调
CentralManager will restore
CentralManager
state.
将会恢复状态
This is when we'll tell you what
与此同时
the current state of the system
我们也会告诉你
is so you can reconcile where we
系统的当前状态
are now versus the time that
以便你可以把当前状态
your application was killed.
跟你的 App 停止的时间两者之间做一个调和
We'll tell you about the
我们将会告诉你
currently connected peripherals
当前所连接的外部设备
and we'll also tell you what we
我们还会告诉你
are scanning for at the time
在重启你的 App 时
that you're relaunched.
我们在搜寻什么
Now there will be times where
有些时候
these can be null as well, so
这些返回的数据都可能是空
you have to be able to be
这意味着
flexible with this and know that
你需要灵活处理这些返回的结果
you can rebuild your state after
并且你要知道在你的 App 重新启动之后
you're relaunched.
你是可以重新恢复你的状态的
Similarly, if you're acting as a
同样
peripheral we can keep doing
如果你作为外设
things on your behalf even after
即使你的 App 不再存在
your application is no longer
我们也可以代替你继续执行操作
and we'll relaunch you when
我们还会帮你重启
that's interesting for your
如果说这种重启对于你的 App 来说
application.
很有趣
So if you had a local service
因此
published in the GATT database
如果你在 GATT 数据库中
or you're advertising a service,
建立了本地服务
we can keep those things going
或者你推广一个服务
and let you know when something
我们可以保持这些服务的正常运行
interesting happens.
当有有趣的事情发生时我们会及时让你知道
Again, you have to start with a
首先
restoration identifier, which
你需要从恢复标识符开始
needs to be unique on the system
这在一个系统中
and we'll tell you the current
是唯一的
state of the system after you
并且在你返回时
come back.
我们会告诉你当前的系统状态
We'll tell you either through
我们将通过状态恢复服务
the restored state services key
来告诉你有什么服务
what services are still
是继续在你的系统上运行的
published on the system for you
我们也会通过状态广告数据
and through the state
来告知你
advertising data key we'll tell
当前正在代表你
you what we're advertising on
进行什么广告
your behalf.
所以
So state preservation and
状态保持和状态恢复
restoration that has actually
已经在一个系统中
been in the system for a couple
存在了很多年了
of years, but this year we've
但是
enhanced it to be even more
今年我们将对此进行升级
reliable for your application.
以使它对于你的 App 来说更加可靠
So we're excited to tell you,
所以
even if there are Bluetooth
我们今天很高兴地告诉你
system level events that
即使曾经
previously would have stopped
总有一些有关蓝牙系统等级的事宜
these things from occurring on
代表你来阻止这一切变为现实
your behalf, we'll keep doing
但是
them for you now.
我们将致力于为你实现这一切
And even if a user reboots the
并且
device, we can keep connecting
即使一个用户重启了设备
to your accessory.
我们也会保持与你配件的连接
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢大家
And one thing we just want to
另外
mention is that in order to keep
我想说一点是
the power profile of these
为了让这些功能的功耗
features low, we actually do
保持一个比较低的水平
have to do a lot of things in
我们在硬件上
Hardware.
下了很多功夫
So, we are limited in the number
所以
of things we can look for at a
我们一次可以查找的东西数量有限
time, especially the number of
特别是
services we can scan for.
我们可以查找的服务数量会受到限制
So the less things you ask for,
所以
the better the chances that we
所需要的东西数量越少
can keep your actions running
我们越可以保证
all the time.
你的请求不间断运行
The other thing about this is
另外一个事情是
there's no UI to control what
没有一个 UI
applications are allowed to do
来控制什么 App
what in the background, so we
可以在后台做什么事情
will stop doing things on your
这意味着
app's behalf if the user either
我们将会在你从任务开关处
force quits the app through the
退出 App 时
task switcher or if the user
停止工作
turns off Bluetooth manually
或者
through Bluetooth settings we'll
当用户从蓝牙设置处
stop doing background activities
手动关闭蓝牙时
on your behalf.
我们将会停止以你的名义进行后台操作
Another thing we've enhanced for
今年我们所改进的
this year is Write Without
另一个内容是
Response.
关于 Write Without Response
So previously you could call
就像 Write Without Response 的名字
Write Without Response, and as
所暗示的那样
the name implies you don't hear
你调用 Write Without Response
anything back from that.
但是你却并不会收到回应
And there are times when your
而且
writes would be dropped if you
如果你向系统中写入了太多的内容
pushed too many into the system.
你写入的内容会被舍弃
And we had no way to tell you
并且
that those packets were dropped
我们没办法告诉你
so if you were trying to send a
有一些数据被丢弃了
large amount of data you had to
所以
come up with schemes to try to
如果你试图传输大量的数据
make sure that that data was
你需要想出一种
reliable.
保证你的数据可靠的方法
For this year, we've enhanced
今年
CBPeripheral with a new property
我们通过一个
called
叫 canSendWriteWithoutResponse 的新特性
canSendWriteWithoutResponse.
来加强了 CB 的外部设备
So if you call this before you
所以
do a write and it and it returns
如果你在写入之前
yes, that's our promise to you
先调用这个函数
that your data will not be
并且
dropped in software before we
这个函数返回了是这一结果
get a chance to send it to the
这意味着你的数据在有机会传输到外部设备之前
remote peripheral.
将不会在软件中被删除
If that returns no, you'll also
如果
get a delegate callback when
返回了否这一结果
we're ready and we'll call back
那么当我们准备就绪时
peripheralIsReady
你还会收到一个委托回调
(toSendWritewithoutResponse.
我们会回调 peripheralIsReady(toSendWritewithoutResponse)
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢
Okay. So when we first launched
好的
in 2011 we support macOS 10.7
所以当我们在 2011 年第一次推出时
and iOS 5.
我们支持 macOS 10.7 和 iOS 5
We supported those this whole
我们一直支持这些
time, and on tvOS 9 we added
并且在 Apple tvOS 9 上
support for tvOS.
我们添加了对 tvOS 的支持
This is actually the first time
这是我们第一次来谈论这件事情
we've been on stage to talk to
所以
you about that so we'd like to
我也想对这件事做一个回顾
go over that as well.
在今年
And new for this year, we're
我们也支持了
supporting watchOS.
watchOS
We think this opens a lot of
我们认为
cool opportunities, especially
这会带来更多的机会
in the health and fitness space
特别是
for places where it was
对于那些
unpractical to bring your phone
带手机不方便的
previously.
健身运动场所
So iOS and macOS were the first
所以 iOS 和 macOS
platforms that we supported.
是我们所支持的第一个平台
They support both foreground and
他们既支持前台 App
background applications, and
也支持后台 App
both central and peripheral mode
既支持中央模式操作
operation.
也支持外围模式操作
We allow you to go down to 15 ms
今年
starting this year for your
我们允许你的连接间隔
connection interval.
下降至 15 ms
So if you're trying to get the
所以
most throughput to your
如果你想你的配件
accessories or the lowest
获得最大的吞吐量
latency, these are the platforms
或者获得最低的延迟
that provide you the most
那么
opportunities there.
这些平台为你提供了最好的机会
And as I mentioned, state
就像我之前说的
preservation and restoration are
iOS 系统支持状态保持
supported on iOS so you can try
和状态恢复
-- maintain connections to your
所以
accessories throughout the day
你可以全天候的
and even across major device
保持与配件的连接
events like a system reboot.
甚至在诸如系统重启这种重要的设备事件发生时也是如此
tvOS was supported as of tvOS 9,
Apple tvOS 9 支持 Apple tvOS
and it was interesting for us
这对于我们来说
because it was the first that we
非常有趣
wanted to support third party
因为
accessories on a platform that
这是我们第一次在一个依靠蓝牙
relies on Bluetooth as the main
作为主要系统输入的平台上
system input.
来尝试支持第三方的配件
So we have to coexist between
所以
those two opportunities or those
我们必须在这两个机会或者说两个活动
two activities.
之间共存
So in this case we had to put
所以
some restrictions into the
在这种情况下
system to make sure that we
我们不得不对系统
don't interfere with core
进行一些限制
operating things like the Apple
以确保像 Apple Siri Remote 这样的核心操作
Siri Remote.
不会受到干扰
So we decided for accessory or
所以我们决定
for tvOS, you can only act as a
对于配件
Central device, and you can only
或者 Apple tvOS
connect to two simultaneous
你只能作为中央设备
devices.
并且你只能连接到两个同步设备
You can be paired with an
你可以匹配无限数量的设备
unlimited amount but you can
但是
only use two at a time.
一次你只能使用两个设备
And we don't allow 15 ms
并且我们在 Apple tvOS 上
connection intervals on tvOS, we
不允许 15 ms 的连接间隔
set the minimum at 30 ms. So
我们设定的最小连接间隔是 30 ms
this still allows you to get low
所以
latency for your accessories and
这仍然可以保证你的配件
good user interaction but it
获得一个比较低的延迟
leaves more system resources
并且也保证了比较好的用户交互性
available.
但是它同时会留下更多可用的系统资源
And when your application is
当你的 App 被暂停
suspended or moved to the
或者
background, we're going to
转到后台运行的时候
automatically disconnect those
我们就会自动
accessories.
把这些配件断开连接
And similarly, to watch OS, tvOS
并且
is a platform that relies on
对于 watchOS 来说
Bluetooth for its core system
Apple tvOS 是一个
functionality.
主要依靠蓝牙来实现其核心系统功能的平台
So we are allowing access to
因此
Core Bluetooth whenever the
只要系统
system allows your application
允许你的 App 运行
to be run.
我们就允许访问核心蓝牙
So if a user is in your
因此
application and directly
如果一个用户
interacting with it, you can use
正在使用你的 App 并直接与其交互
Core Bluetooth.
你可以使用核心蓝牙
You can connect your
你可以连接你的配件
accessories, you can interact
你也可以与它们交互
with them, but this also means
这也意味着
that if you're allowed to run
如果你因为其他原因
for other reasons, like
而被允许运行时
complication updates or a
比如复杂更新和试验会话
workout session, you can stay
你可以保持
connected to your accessories
与你配件的连接
and continue getting that data.
并且持续的获取这些数据
Similarly, if the tvOS -- you
同样
can only act as a Central,
如果你的 Apple tvOS
meaning that you can connect out
只能作为中央设备
tier accessories but you can't
这意味着
act as a peripheral to other
你可以连接线配件
devices.
但是你不能作为其他设备的外部设备使用
And the same two simultaneous
并且
connection limitation is in
在 watchOS 与 Apple tvOS 上
place on watchOS as on tvOS, and
也有两个同步连接
the same connection interval
和相同的
limitation.
连接间隔的限制
Also, when the system decides
此外
that your application needs to
当系统认为
be suspended, that's the
你的 App 需要被暂停时
indication to Core Bluetooth
这意味着
that the accessories connected
核心蓝牙会把所有
on that application's behalf
因为该 App 所连接的配件
should be disconnected.
都断开连接
And this is supported on Apple
这已经
Watch Series 2.
被 Apple Watch 系列 2 支持
As I mentioned, we think this is
就像我之前说的一样
a really cool opportunity to see
我们认为
accessories connected to Apple
可以让 Apple Watch 连接配件
Watch and can be used all day.
并且全天候使用这些配件是非常有前景的
You can be in places where you
你可以去到一些
don't want to bring your phone
不方便携带手机的地方
or places where it's just more
或者是一些
convenient to have data
你可以方便地使用 Apple Watch
available on your wrist.
来获取所需数据的地方
So if you want things like
所以
battery updates throughout the
如果你想
day, your complication can
全天实时更新你的电池
connect your accessory, get a
你可以连接你的配件
quick bit of data, and always be
来获取快速的数据
up to date on the home screen.
并且实时更新在主屏幕上
New for this year, we're
今年还有的一个创新是
allowing access to L2CAP
我们允许
Channels.
访问 L2CAP 信道
So, an L2CAP channel at the
因此
lowest level is just this stream
最底层的 L2CAP 信道
of data between two devices, and
就是两个设备之间的
it's actually the protocol that
数据流
we use under the covers for all
实际上
communication between these
这是我们在这些设备之间
devices.
进行通信所使用的协议
So L2CAP Channels have been used
所以我们在我们的平台上
on the platform.
使用了 L2CAP 信道
Since day one of Bluetooth this
这是第一次
is the first time that we're
我们让你的 App
opening up for your applications
可以
to directly talk over these
直接使用
channels.
这些信道
It actually stands for the
它实际上
Logical Link Control and
代表了逻辑链路控制
Adaptation Protocol, and the
和适配协议
support for dynamically
也代表了
allocated connection or into
对于动态分配连接的支持
channels is new for Bluetooth
或者进入信道对于
Core Spec 4.1.
蓝牙核心规范 4.1 来说是全新的
So unlike all the other
所以
interactions that you've done
不像你之前
with your accessories before
在你配件中使用的交互方式
where you have to work through
比如
the GATT Database to get your
使用 GATT 数据库
data, L2CAP Channels allow you
来获取你的数据
to open a side channel and
现在 L2CAP 信道
directly read and write without
允许你开启一个侧面信道
any framing limitations, packet
从而不受框架限制
size limitations.
和数据包大小限制的直接读取和写入
It's a direct way to talk
这是你的设备
between your device and your
和配件之间的
accessory.
直接交流方式
So we think this API is very
所以
simple to use.
我们认为这个 API 使用起来非常简单
If you have already connected to
如果
a peripheral, all you have to do
你已经连接到一个外部设备
is call openL2CAPChannel and
则只需调用
specify as the PSM, and you'll
openL2CAPChannel
get a callback data
并指定为 PSM
openL2CAPChannel will hand you
并且您将获得一个回调数据
back the object that represents
openL2CAPChannel 将会返回
this channel.
表示此信道的对象
So the PSM is a -- it's the
所以 PSM 是一个
Protocol Service Multiplexer but
一个协议服务多路复用器
you should think of it as
但你可以把它看作
analogous to say TCP port.
类似于 TCP 端口的东西
It's just a number that you give
你只需要
to us that uniquely identifies
给我们一个数字
the service you want to open on
来表明
the peripheral side of the
你想要在外部设备连接上
connection.
使用的服务
And what's interesting about
有趣的是
this is that there are some
一些由蓝牙 SIG
profiles that are published by
给出的
the Bluetooth SIG that have a
配置文件
hard coded PSM.
有硬编码的 PSM
So if you're trying to do things
所以
like the Object Transfer
如果你想要尝试
Protocol, the PSM will be known
Object Transfer Protocol 这种东西
to you even before you connect
在连接到设备之前
to the device.
你就会知道 PSM
But in every other case, the PSM
但是
is unique to the device you're
在别的例子中
talking to, which means it's
PSM 对于一个你要连接的设备来说是独一无二的
locally assigned and can even be
所以这意味着 PSM 是本地分配的
reused by other applications.
并且可以被其他 App 重复使用
So it's important that you
所以
discover what PSM to connect to
在你想要建立连接时
before you try to open it.
你需要先知道你要连接的 PSM 是什么 这很重要
What we've done to make this a
我们做了一些事情
little bit simpler is we're
来让这件事变得容易一些
publishing a UUID that you can
我们推出了 UUID
use and put within your service
你可以使用 UUID
to help you specify what PSM to
并把它放置到你的服务中
open that's associated with your
它可以帮助你确定
CB service.
哪些与你的 CB 服务相关联的 PSM 需要打开
We're also opening L2CAP
如果
Channels if you're acting as a
你作为一个外部设备
peripheral.
我们也会打开 L2CAP 信道
So if you want to have a L2CAP
所以
Channel that's associated with
如果你想要你的服务
your service, you can call
使用 L2CAP 信道
publishL2CAPChannel and we will
你可以调用 publishL2CAPChannel
return you what PSM was assigned
然后
by the system in the callback
我们会在 peripheralManger didPublishL2CAPChannel 的回调中
peripheralManger
返回给你
didPublishL2CAPChannel.
所被系统分配的 PSM
Another thing we've allowed is
我们允许的
we allow you to specify whether
另一件事情是
your L2CAP Channel requires
我们允许你指定
encryption or not.
你的 L2CAP 是否要加密
So most of the time, the safe
大多数情况下
bet is to say yes, I want
人们出于对安全的考虑
encryption.
会选择加密
It protects you from things like
它可以
man-in-the-middle attacks, it
保护你
protects you from things like
免受中间人攻击
people eavesdropping on the
它也可以
packets that you're sending
保护你在两个设备之间发送数据包时
between your two devices.
免受别人的窃听
But there are time when you
但是
might want to build more
有些时候你会想建立
advanced types of
更高级别的身份验证
authentication, like using
比如
public key cryptography you
使用公钥加密技术
could build your own account
通过公钥
system and protect your data
你可以建立你自己的账户系统
that way.
并且可以以此保护你的数据
So let's go through an example
所以
of how you would actually
让我们看一个如何在两设备间
negotiate an L2CAP Channel
协商一个 L2CAP 信道的
between two devices.
实例
If you're acting as a
如果
peripheral, you would ask the
你作为一个外部设备
system to publish an L2CAP
你可以要求系统
Channel.
开启一个 L2CAP 通道
Again you get to specify whether
并且
this channel requires encryption
你需要指定这个信道
or not.
是否需要加密
In this case we're going to say
在这个例子中
true.
我们使用加密
And when that's successful,
当信道建立成功后，
you'll get a callback
你会得到一个
peripheralManager
peripheralManager didPublishL2CAPChannel
didPublishL2CAPChannel.
的回调
And as I mentioned, we'll tell
就像我之前说的一样
you what PSM has been locally
我会告诉你
assigned for your service.
你的服务被本地分配了什么 PSM
So this is your opportunity to
所以
make the PSM known to incoming
这是让连接知道 PSM 的方法
connections so that they can
这样一来
discover what channel to open
就可以知道你的服务
that's associated with your
需要开启
service.
哪个信道
As a Central, you can read the
作为中央设备
PSM and that's all the
你可以读取 PSM
information you need to actually
然后
open that channel.
你可以用这个信息来打开通道
So now you can call
所以现在
openL2CAPChannel with the PSM
你可以使用
that you read from the remote
你从远程设备读取到的 PSM
device and you'll get the
来调用 openL2CAPChannel
callback didOpenL2CAPChannel.
然后你就可以得到 didOpenL2CAPChannel 的回调
So CB L2CAP Channel encapsulates
所以
all the information you need to
CB L2CAP 信道封装了你所需要的所有信息
know who you're talking to and
以便知道你在与谁交流
how you can talk to it.
以及如何与之交流
In this case we tell you the
在这种情况下
peer, which is either the
对等体既可以是远程连接的中央设备
central or the peripheral on the
也可以是
remote side of the connection.
远程连接的外部设备
We tell you what PSM was
我们
connected in case you have
将会告诉你 PSM 已被和什么连接
multiple services that you've
以防
published.
你有多个已建立的服务
And then we just give you an
然后
InputStream and OutputStream.
我们会给你 InputStream 和 OutputStream
We didn't want to build our own
我们不想建立我们自己的 API
API and make you have to learn
这样会
how to use a new Read Write API.
让你需要重新学习一个新的读写 API
We didn't want you to have to
我们不想让你
adapt your code to deal
因为
specifically with Bluetooth
蓝牙连接
connections.
而改变你的代码
If you already know how to deal
如果
with the socket and an
你已经知道如何处理
InputStream and OutputStream,
socket InputStream 和 OutputStream
you can deal with an L2CAP
你就可以
Channel.
处理好 L2CAP 信道
So we use all the same stream
所以
events that you would get off
我们使用一样的流事件
of, say, a socket after you're
你可以在连接后
connected, and there's bytes
摆脱 socket
available to be read.
但是数据还是可以持续被读取
You'll get the callback
你会得到
hasBytesAvailable.
hasBytesAvailable 的回调
If you're writing data and you
如果你正在写入数据
fill all those queues, you get
并填写所有这些队列
the same callback you would on a
你将会得到与 hasSpaceAvailable 的 socket 一样的
socket of hasSpaceAvailable.
回调
We think this is really powerful
我们认为
because if you already have code
这是非常强大的
that knows how to talk over
因为如果你已经有
other network interfaces like
可以在别的网络接口
Ethernet or Wi-Fi.
如以太网和无线网上运行的程序
That code can be directly
则
adapted to run on top of L2CAP
这个程序可以被直接
Channels.
应用于 L2CAP 信道中
And when the channel has been
在信道
closed, you get the same
关闭以后
endEncountered.Event that you
你会得到相同的
would get.
endEncountered.Event
So after you've opened your
所以
connection, you can read data to
当你打开你的连接之后
that connection, you can write
你可以向那个连接读取数据
to it.
你也可以向它写入数据
Eventually when it's closed you
最终
get the endEncounterd.Event, and
当它关闭时
it can be closed for a couple of
你可以获取 endEncounterd.Event
reasons.
并且这种关闭可以由于很多原因
So if the overall Bluetooth link
所以
is lost we'll tell you that the
如果蓝牙链接丢失
L2CAP Channel has been closed.
我们将会告诉你 L2CAP 信道被关闭
As the Central side, you can
作为中央设备
manually ask to close that
你可以手动操作
connection.
关闭连接
Now on the peripheral side, you
作为外部设备
can either un-publish the
你可以取消发布服务
service or if you drop the
或者
object and allow it to be
你可以放弃对象
deallocated that's an implicit
并允许它被释放
sign to us through Core
这会通过核心蓝牙
Bluetooth that you're no longer
告诉我们
interested.
你对此不再感兴趣
That will also close the L2CAP
这也会
Channel.
关闭 L2CAP 信道
So when should you use L2CAP
所以什么时候
Channels?
你可以用 L2CAP 信道呢
In general, if you're already
通常来说
doing well with GATT and your
如果你已经熟练使用 GATT
data model fits well into a GATT
并且你的数据模型
database, you should continue
与 GATT 数据库可以完美兼容
using that.
那么你应该继续这样使用
GATT makes it very simple to
GATT 使恢复数据
discover your data, to get quick
和快速更新
updates.
都变得很容易
You don't have to frame any of
你不需要
your data.
构建你的数据
So keep using that if that
所以如果可行 你可以继续保持
worked for you.
原先的使用方法
But if there are times where it
但是如果之前
was previously hard to make your
让你的数据适应 GATT 数据库时有困难
data fit into the GATT database,
要么是因为
either because you had more data
你的数据太多
that you could fit into a
或者是因为
characteristic, or you're
GATT 跟这些数据
finding that GATT is kind of
有些不兼容
getting in the way, L2CAP
这时
Channels are a great opportunity
L2CAP 信道就是
to get the lowest overhead best
让你的配件间
performance when talking between
交流得更好的
your accessories.
绝佳机会
And if you're doing large data
并且
transfers, say like a firmware
如果你在做大规模的数据传输
update, L2CAP Channels are a
比如说固件更新
good opportunity to help you get
L2CAP 通道就是一个让这种数据传输
it there faster.
更加迅速的绝佳机会
And if you have a streaming
如果
protocol that's already defined
你已经在你的两台设备间
somewhere that you want to run
定义了一个流媒体协议
between your two devices, L2CAP
那么
Channels make that a really
L2CAP 会使其
natural fit.
非常合适
I'd like to talk to you about
我想
some of the best practices that
向你介绍一些
we've learned over the years.
我们最近几年所得到的经验
So the first one I have, please
第一条就是
follow the Bluetooth Accessory
请按照
Design Guidelines.
蓝牙配件设计指南操作
We have a great set of
我们的指南
guidelines that are published
有很多的内容
that give you lots of data to
里面有大量的信息
help you build the best
这些都可以帮助你
accessories.
建立最好的配件
They're not mandatory but they
这些指南
are things we've learned over
并不是强制性的
the year that help you build
但是它们
accessories without running into
是我们这些年间
the same pitfalls and problems
所学到的经验
that we've seen across the
它们可以帮助你
years.
在建立配件时少走弯路
And if possible, use existing
如果有条件的话
profiles and services.
请使用现成的配置文件和服务
We've defined our own protocols
对于
for things like Notification
像 Notification Center
Center and Apple Media, and the
和 Apple Media 这种
Bluetooth site has a bunch of
我们已经定义了
really good profiles for things
我们自己的协议
like batter updates and device
并且蓝牙网站上
information.
有很多像关于电池更新和设备信息的配置文件
So if there's already a profile
所以
that does what you need,
如果有一些
implement that and it will help
现成的配置文件可用
you get a head start on getting
你应该使用它
the data you want.
这将会帮助你更快的获取你所要的数据
A common question we get is,
我们经常遇到的
"Why does it take so long to
一个问题是
connect to my accessory?"
“为什么经常需要花费那么久来连接到我的配件”
So before your two devices are
在你的两个设备
connected, they're each running
建立连接之前
on their own timelines.
它们是各自运行在自己的时间线上的
Your peripheral is going to be
你的外部设备
advertising things to the world,
会像外界传播信息
and your Central is going to be
你的中央设备
looking for devices that are
会从外界
around.
搜索设备
But each one of these uses small
但是
windows, and until those two
每个事件都使用小窗口
events line up you can't
并且直到这两个事件排好
discover your accessory.
你才可以查找到你的配件
So the easiest way you can get a
所以
quick connection between your
在你的两个设备间
two devices or a quick discovery
建立快速连接
when you're scanning is to use
或者在你扫描时
the shortest advertising
快速发现的最简单方法是
interval possible.
使用最短的广告间隔
That ensures that no matter what
这保证了
state your central is in,
无论你的中央设备
whether it's screen on, screen
处于什么状态
off, directly in the app, in the
屏幕开启屏幕关闭
background, it will get you the
直接在 App 中还是在后台运行
shortest time to find.
你都可以使用最短的时间查找
Now using a short advertising
对你的配件
interval takes extra battery for
使用较短的广告间隔
your accessory, so you can't do
会增加额外的电池使用
that all the time but what we
所以
strongly recommend is if you
你不能长时间的做这件事情
know through any means
但是我们强烈推荐的是
necessary, through the user
如果你能通过一些必要手段
touching the accessory, user
比如通过用户触摸配件
picking it up, accelerometer,
用户拾起
buttons, use that as an
加速度计
indication to start doing
按钮等方式
aggressive advertising and then
来作为开始进行活跃广告的暗示
you can go into a lower
这样
advertising interval later when
当你试图节省电池使用的时候
you're trying to save battery.
你也可以有一个较低的广告间隔
If you're trying to save
如果
battery, you can go to the
你想要节省电池
Bluetooth Accessory Design
你可以查询
Guidelines.
蓝牙配件设计指南
We have a whole bunch of power
我们
optimized but also discovery
有很多电源优化
time optimize advertising
我们也发现了
intervals you can use.
可以用于广告间隔的时间优化
Another thing that we see is
我们发现的另一件事情是
that if you've previously used
如果你之前
an accessory and you want to
使用过一个配件
reconnect to that accessory you
并且你想再次连接这一配件时
don't have to scan every time.
不需要每次都进行扫描
If you know that the device is
如果
advertising or you just want to
你知道设备正在广告
connect as quickly as possible,
或者
connect directly to the
你只是想尽快连接
accessory.
直接连上配件
If you have the identifier, you
如果
can call retrievePeripherals
你有标识符
(WithIdentifiers) and directly
你可以调用
get a CBPeripheral object that
retrievePeripherals(WithIdentifiers)
you can connect to.
然后直接获取一个你可以连接的 CBPeripheral 对象
If you were to scan for your
如果
accessory and then connect to it
你想要扫描你的配件
it's actually going to take us
然后连接到它
twice as long to do that
与第一次发现就连接相比 它实际上
operation as if we could have
会花费我们
connected the first time we
两倍的时间
found it.
来完成该操作
Something we get asked a lot is
我们
why does it take so long to
常常被问到的一个问题是
discover the GATT database after
为什么在我连接到我的配件后
I've connected to my accessory?
查找 GATT 数据库要花费那么久
And in this case there's a
有一些方法
couple of things you can do to
可以让你加速
speed that up.
这个进程
The first recommendation we have
我们
is use as few services or
首先推荐的方法是
characteristics as possible.
尽可能少的使用服务或特性
Every time you add a service to
每次你向 GATT 数据库
your GATT Database, that takes
新添加一项服务
extra time over the air that we
都会多花费一些时间
have to ask for those services
因为我们需要查找这些服务
and discover those.
并请求这些服务
So by getting rid of services
所以
that you don't need, or packing
通过舍弃一些
multiple characteristics into
你不需要的服务
one service, that speeds up your
或者将几个特性都压缩进一个服务
service discovery every time
可以在你的用户连接到你的配件时
your user connects to your
大大加快服务查找
accessory.
所需的时间
Another one that's a really
另外一个
simple thing you can do but that
简单有效的办法是
helps is group your services by
你可以依据 UUID 的大小
the UUID size.
来对你的服务进行分组
So if you have multiple 16 bit
所以
UUIDs and then a service with
如果你有多个 16 位 UUID
128 bit UUID we can discover all
有一个 128 位的 UUID 服务
the 16 bit services in one
我们可以在一次往返过程中
roundtrip instead of having to
发现所有的 16 位服务
go back and forth for every
而不是来来回回地
service.
查找每一个服务
And then finally to speed up
最终
your service discovery, if we
你查找服务的过程
can cash your GATT database we
就可以被加速
actually will, so that on
如果我们可以兑现你的 GATT 数据库
reconnect we don't have to
我们一定会这样子做的
discover anything.
这样在重连时我们就不需要再进行查找
If you're in an Accessory that
如果
requires pairing or bonding,
你的配件需要配对
that means that you have to have
或绑定
the service change
这意味着
characteristic in your GATT
你需要修改 GATT 数据库中
database.
服务的特性
The Service Change
服务更改特性
Characteristic is part of the
是蓝牙规范的一部分
Bluetooth Spec that allows you
这允许你告诉我们
to tell us when the services and
你设备上的服务和特性
characteristics on your device
是在什么时候被改变的
have changed and when it's safe
并且告诉我们
for us to reuse the last known
什么时候重新使用
version of the GATT Database.
最新版本的 GATT 数据库是安全的
And if you're an Accessory that
如果
does not allow pairing or
你的配件不允许配对
bonding, this means that if you
或者绑定
have the Service Changed
这意味着
characteristic we can't cache
即使你有服务更改特性
your database anymore.
我们也无法缓存你的数据库
So in those cases, if you do not
所以在这些情况下
have a Serviced Changed
如果
characteristic, we will cache
你没有服务更改特性
your entire service database
我们将会
which gives you quick
缓存你的整个服务数据库
reconnections to your device.
这可以让你更快地重连到设备
But you have to be careful if
但是
you do not support pairing and
如果你不支持配对
you want to do things like
或者你想要做一些固件更新
firmware update.
你就需要更加注意
Even if it's a rare event,
即使这是一个很罕见的事
there's no way for you tell us
但是
that the services have changed
你无法告诉我们
on your peripheral.
你的外部设备上的服务被更改了
And then, finally, if you are
最终
building a new accessory we
如果你想
recommend that you always look
建立一个新的配件
and see the newest chipsets that
你可以经常查看
are available to you.
那些可用的最新的芯片集
Since we came out with Core
因为我们推出了核心蓝牙
Bluetooth, Bluetooth 4.2 and now
蓝牙 4.2 和现在的蓝牙 5.0
5.0 have been released.
都已经发布
All the features in those
这些版本的
releases are backwards
所有功能
compatible.
都是反向兼容的
So even if you build an
所以
accessory that's Bluetooth 5.0,
即使你建立一个蓝牙 5.0 版本的配件
it will work with all the Apple
它也可以
devices that you want to connect
跟所有你想要连接的
to that are 4.0 only.
蓝牙 4.0 版本的设备兼容
And then, like I said, follow
之后就像我说的一样
the Accessory Design Guidelines.
遵从配件设计指南
If you read through those
如果你先阅读这些内容
upfront it can save you a lot of
你可以在之后的项目中
hassle later in your project.
省却很多麻烦
Now I'd like to hand it to Duy,
现在我想把舞台
who's going to walk through how
让给 Duy
to get the most out of Core
Duy 将会告诉大家
Bluetooth.
如何充分使用核心蓝牙
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Craig.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Craig
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; I am Duy.
&gt;&gt; 我是 Duy
Today I'll talk about getting
今天
the most out of Core Bluetooth.
我将谈论一下如何充分使用核心蓝牙
Let's walk through a scenario
让我们
where we have a lot of data to
想象一个场景
send from where updating a
我们要从一个更新设备的地方
device.
发送大量数据
Today it takes about 3,000
如果
seconds to transfer 1MB of data
我们使用 Write With Response
at about 2.5kbps if we use Write
和所有的默认设置
With Response and all defaults.
以 2.5 kbps 的速度 我们需要花费 3000 秒来传输 1 MB 的数据
So this is obviously very slow.
这非常的慢
What are the problems?
那么问题是什么呢
There's two main problems.
主要有两个问题
The first is all of the protocol
第一个问题是
overhead in LE.
LE 中的所有协议开销
The Bluetooth Specification
蓝牙规范
defines the LE maximum
将 LE 的最大应用数据链
application datalink to be 27
定义为 27 字节
Bytes, but we lose 7 of that
但是
because your data has to
因为你的数据
traverse from the application
需要从 App
through GATT, through ATT and
到 GATT
through L2CAP, so you lose about
到 ATT
25% of the packet, and in the
再到 L2CAP
end the useable data length is
这将会丢失 7 字节的数据 所以你丢失了数据包中 25 % 的内容
only 20 Bytes.
最终可用数据长度将只有 20 字节
And in addition, once your data
并且
gets through the controller the
一旦你的数据
hardware also adds link layer
通过了控制器
security and CRC which adds even
硬件会添加链路层安全
more time to transmit a packet.
并且 CRC 也会延长传输数据包的时间
So in order to improve
所以
performance, we'll have to
为了提高性能
reduce both the software and
我们需要同时减小
hardware overhead.
硬件与软件的开销
The second problem is previously
第二个问题是
in GATT the only way to reliably
以前在 GATT 中
write is to use Write With
可靠写入的唯一方法是
Response which take two
使用 Write With Response
intervals to complete, one to
这要花费两个时间间隔来完成
write and one to wait for the
一个时间间隔来写入
response.
另一个时间间隔来回复
So your writes are actually very
所以
sparse.
你的写入是非常稀疏的
You're not fully utilizing the
你没有
available bandwidth because, as
充分利用可用的带宽
you know, there's multiple
因为
opportunities to transmit per
有很多方法可以让每个时间间隔
interval and we want to pack as
都进行传输
many writes as we can into all
并且我们在所有的连接事件中
of the connection events.
都想打包尽可能多的写入内容
So how do we do this?
所以我们要怎么实现这一切呢
As Craig mentioned, we've
就像 Craig 之前提到的一样
improved Write Without Response.
我们改进了 Write Without Response
You can now write and continue
你现在可以写入
to write into Core Bluetooth
并且
sets can send holds write
继续写入
without response to false, in
核心蓝牙 设置可以发送保持写入信号
which case then your application
而不出现错误响应
can wait for a delegate to
在这种情况下
signal when it's safe to resume
你的 App 会等待一个委托信号
writing.
来在安全时恢复写入
And when you follow the APIs the
并且当你遵循 API 时
write will be reliable.
写入会是可靠的
And you can use the Write
并且
Without Response to make sure
你可以使用 Write Without Response
that Core Bluetooth is
来确保核心蓝牙
sufficiently buffered so we can
是充分缓冲的
use all of the available
这样我们就可以使用
connection events to send all of
所有可用的连接事件
your application data.
来传输你的应用数据
And in iOS 10, we also enlarged
在 iOS 10 中
the Connection Event Length so
我们也增大了连接事件长度
now you have even more room to
这样你就会有更多的空间
write using Write For That
来使用
Response.
Write For That Response 写入
And when you pack all of the
当你把所有的连接事件
connection events in all of the
打包进一个时间间隔后
interval, your throughput will
你的吞吐量
improve from 2.5 to 37 kbps.
将会从 2.5 kbps 提升至 37 kbps
And coming back to reducing
然后
software protocol overhead, all
我们回到减少软件协议开销的问题
of the discussion thus far
所有我们的讨论
assumes an ATT MTU of 23 Bytes,
都假设一个 23 字节的 ATT MTU
this is why there are red
这也是为什么
portion overhead in each viewer
每个观众包都有红色部分的开销
packets but we can enlarge the
但是我们可以扩展 MTU
MTU and enlarge the writes to
并扩展写入内容
align to the MTU.
以适应 MTU
This will improve your
这将会提高
throughput because L2CAP will
你的吞吐量
now fragment your data for you.
因为 L2CAP 将会把你的数据分块
You only have to pay in overhead
你只需要
on the first fragment of your
在你 MTU 的第一块数据上
MTU.
分配花销
The rest of the fragments can be
其余的数据块
as the full 27 Bytes, so when
可以达到 27 字节
you do this your throughput
所以当你在做这些的时候
should improve to 48 kbps.
你的吞吐量会提高至 48 kbps
And so how do you configure MTU
然后
in Core Bluetooth?
你要怎样在核心蓝牙中配置 MTU 呢
If you're running Core Bluetooth
如果
to Core Bluetooth, there's
你是从核心蓝牙运行到核心蓝牙
nothing much you have to do.
那么你没有什么可以做的
We will calculate the MTU for
我们将会
you based on the connection
根据连接事件长度
event length and other system
和系统配置
configurations but in this
来为你计算 MTU
example we're from we're
但是在这个例子中
updating an accessory.
我们正在更新配件
So if you recall the ATT MTU
所以
exchange as a transaction
如果你回忆一个
between the client and the
客户端与服务器间的 ATT MTU 交换
server, so the two minimum of
则两个建议值的两个最小值
the -- the minimum of the two
就是 ATT MTU
proposed value is actually the
所以
ATT MTU, so your accessory
你的配件
should also use a large MTU to
应该使用更大的 MTU
take advantage of this more
来充分利用这些
optimized behavior.
更加优化的特性
And to use a large MTU that's
并且
aligned to the -- to use a
要使用更大的写属性
larger attribute write that is
来适应 MTU
aligned to the MTU, you can use
对此
the below interfaces to look at
你可以使用下面的接口
what is the maximum write length
来找出 MTU 适用的
aligned to the MTU.
最大写入长度
So thus far we've talked about
到此
how to pack as much writes as we
我们探讨了
can into the intervals and how
如何在一个时间间隔中
to utilize -- fully utilize all
打包尽可能多的写入内容
of the bandwidth available.
并且谈论了如何充分利用可用带宽
We talked about how to reduce
我们讨论了如何减小开销
overhead, software overhead.
软件开销
But the fact that LE is 27 Bytes
但是
per packet and we have to pay
LE 每个数据包 27 字节
the hardware overhead per
并且
packet, this really limits how
我们得为每个数据包提供硬件开销
much further we can improve LE
这大大限制了
performance using just software.
我们仅仅通过软件可以提高的 LE 性能
So we've added extended data
所以
length support.
我们添加了扩展数据长度支持
Extended data length is a 4.2
扩展数据长度
feature that increases the
是 4.2 的一个功能
maximum application data length
它可以把应用数据长度
from 27 to 251.
从 27 字节提升至 251 字节
This means that per packet now
这意味着
you can send 10 times the amount
每个数据包中你可以比之前
of data so you've eliminated all
多传输十倍的数据
of the hardware overhead and
所以你就可以
software overhead previously and
消除所有的硬件开销和软件开销
we can now use more of the
并且
available time to transmit your
我们可以使用更多的可用时间
application data.
来传输你的应用数据
And in fact, we can send a full
事实上
-- an entire maximum GATTs write
我们可以使用扩展数据长度
of 512 Bytes in a single
在一个时间间隔里
interval using Extended Data
发送一个完整的
Length, and this should be about
512 字节的 GATT 写入
3 times the throughput of your
这是
normal performance.
正常吞吐量的三倍
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Extended Data Length is the new
扩展数据长度
feature in Bluetooth 4.2.
是蓝牙 4.2 中的新功能
It extends the maximum
它将最大应用数据长度
application data length from 27
从 27
to 251.
扩展到 251
It's completely transparent to
这对于你的 App 来说
your application.
是完全透明的
If you're running Core Bluetooth
如果
to Core Bluetooth we've done
你是从核心蓝牙运行到核心蓝牙
everything for you.
那么我们已经为你做好了一切
We'll negotiate the write data
我们会根据你的硬件配置
length and MTU appropriate to
协商写入合适的数据长度和 MTU
your hardware configuration, but
但是
in this example again we're
在这个例子中
updating a firmware device so
我们在更新固件设备
remember you have to also add
所以
support for extended data length
你还需要在配件中
in the accessory for this to
为扩展数据长度
work.
添加支持
And it has four times the
并且
throughput in the same amount of
它是非常节能的
radio time so it's also very
因为在同样的广播时间中
power efficient.
它有四倍的吞吐量
It's now available on iPhone 7
它现在
and Apple Watch Series 2, and
可以在 iPhone 7 和 Apple Watch Series 2
the newly announced iPad Pro.
以及新推出的 iPad Pro 上使用
So please try it out and use
所以
this as a reference to develop
请尝试着使用一下
your new Extended Data Length
并且把它作为一个
Accessory.
开发你自己的扩展数据长度配件的参考
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And because we're -- the example
因为
is from we're updating a device,
我们的例子是基于更新设备
this is a good example of where
所以这也是一个
you should use L2CAP Connection
有关使用
Oriented Channel.
L2CAP 面向连接信道的例子
This will eliminate all of the
这将会
overhead previously in GATT and
消除所有之前 GATT 和 ATT 中的开销
ATTs, but more importantly it
但是更重要的是
eliminates limitations and
它消除了 GATT 中的限制
restriction in GATT like the
比如之前的 GATT
maximum attribute size of 512,
限制最大属性大小为 512
so we can now write much larger
所以我们现在可以写入更大的值
values and use much larger MTU.
也可以使用更大的 MTU
When we do that the throughput
当我们这样做的时候
will increase to almost 200
吞吐量会增加至
kbps.
接近 200 kbps
This really shows how powerful
这证明了
Extended Data Length can be if
如果没有了软件协议的限制
it is not limited by software
扩展数据长度
protocol.
将会多么强大
As you know, another way to
众所周知
improve performance is to ask
提升性能的另一方法是
for a faster connection
请求一个更快的
interval.
连接间隔
All of the discussion thus far
所有至今为止的讨论
assumes a connection interval of
都假设连接间隔为 30 ms
30 ms, but in Core Bluetooth we
但是
made a change to lower the
在核心蓝牙中
connection interval minimum for
我们把 iOS 中的连接间隔
iOS to 15 ms, so when your
减小至 15 ms
firmware is updating your device
所以当你的固件
you can ask for a parameter
在更新你的设备时
update request and set the
你可以请求一个参数更新
interval min and max to 15 ms in
并将时间间隔的最小值和最大值
which we will honor.
设置为 15 ms
And when you do that, your
当你这么做了以后
throughput can double to 394,
你的吞吐量
almost 400 kbps.
可以翻倍至 394 也就是接近 400 kbps
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So this is a summary of where we
接下来是一个关于我们做过的事
were and where we are now.
和我们正要做的事的总结
We started with Write With
我们
Response at 2.5 kbps.
从 2.5 kbps 的 Write With Response 开始
Then we did Write Without
接着我们做出了 Write Without Response
Response but writing only once
但是
per interval, which only doubles
每个时间间隔只能写入一次
the performance.
这只是将性能翻倍而已
But if you packed all of the
但是
opportunities to transmit with
如果你打包所有传输机会
writes your throughput can
你的吞吐量
improve to 37.
可以增加至 37 kbps
And if you reduce overhead using
并且
larger MTU, your performance can
如果你使用更大的 MTU 来减小开销
go up to 48 kbps.
你的性能可以提高至 48 kbps
And we made a major leap forward
接着我们在扩展数据长度上
with Extended Data Length and
实现了一个重要的跨越
tripled that which will yield
我们把它提高至三倍
135 kbps.
这将性能提高至 135 kbps
And if we eliminate the software
如果
limitations using L2CAP plus
我们用 L2CAP 和扩展数据长度
Extended Data Length, it can
来消除软件限制
improve to almost 200 kbps.
性能可以被提升至 200 kbps
And we increase the -- made the
然后
connection interval faster which
我们加快连接间隔
allows you to transmit more
这让你可以更频繁的传输数据
often, then the throughput will
这样吞吐量
improve to 400 kbps.
可以被提升至 400 kbps
So we started with about 3,000
所以
seconds to download 1 MB of data
我们从最初的
and we end it with 20 seconds to
花费 3000 秒来下载 1 MB 数据
download 1 MB of data.
慢慢提高到了现在的 20 秒下载 1 MB 数据
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So in summary, please request a
所以 总的来说
shorter connection interval.
请请求一个更短的连接间隔
The new minimum is 15 MS on iOS
当前 iOS 下的最新最小值
if you need it.
是 15 MS
Take advantage of all the GATT
请尽情的使用我们所有的 GATT 的优化
optimizations we have like Write
比如
Without Response.
Write Without Response
Use L2CAP Channel for larger
使用 L2CAP 信道
transfer.
来做大规模数据传输
All of this is free and all in
这些都是免费的 都是软件的形式
software, and also update your
你还需要根据最新的蓝牙规范
hardware with the latest
和硬件标准
specification of Bluetooth
更新你的硬件
Specification and Hardware for
以得到
best performance and best
最好的性能
battery life.
和电池寿命
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Duy.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Duy
So we've talked about a lot of
所以
really exciting stuff here.
我们今天谈论了很多很振奋人心的信息
There's a lot to go over, but if
有很多需要回顾的东西
you're the type of Application
但是
that wants to be connected
如果你的 App
throughout the day, look into
是希望整天都连接的
the new optimizations we've put
你可以查看我们状态恢复中的
in for State Restoration.
最新优化
Try to build more reliable
尝试为你的用户
experiences for your customers.
建立更稳定的服务
If it makes sense, you can now
你可以现在
take your existing applications
让你的 App
and make them available to
也适用于 Apple tvOS
people on tvOS and watchOS.
和 watchOS
If you're trying to do things
如果你想要尝试流媒体协议
like streaming protocols or
或者
transfer a large amount of data,
传输大规模数据
L2CAP Channels are a great fit
L2CAP 是一个很好的选择
for that and we think that's a
并且
really powerful feature that's
我们相信这也是一个
going to help you build even
可以帮助你建立更好配件的
better accessories.
强大功能
And then if you're building new
如果
accessories, always look for the
你想要建立新的配件
newest Bluetooth specifications
你要经常查看最新的蓝牙规范
and chipsets available and
和芯片集
follow the Accessory Design
并且
Guidelines.
谨遵配件设计指南
For more information, we have a
这里
website up here that will have
有一个我们的网站
links to the Core Bluetooth
上面有一些
Developer Documentation Sample
关于核心蓝牙开发人员文档示例代码的链接
Code and other great resources
也有一些别的资源
to help you get started.
这些可能会对你有一些帮助
We also have two historical
在 WWDC
sessions that we've done at WWDC
也有两个会议
that are available online, so
可以在线观看
you can go back and watch the
所以你可以回去看这些视频
videos and get a bunch of great
然后获得一些
information about Core Bluetooth
关于核心蓝牙做中央设备
both as a Central and a
或者外部设备
Peripheral.
的信息
Thank you.
谢谢大家
We can't wait to see build with
我们迫不及待的看到大家
all these new enhancements.
使用这些新的技术